<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Fresno Rabbit Drive</title>
            <author>Yoon Hwa Park</author>
            <author>Brian Yee</author>
            <author>Anna Yang</author>
			<author>Rebecca Cardenas</author>
			<author>Vanessa Gomez</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Colleen Jaurretche</publisher>
            <date when="2016">Fall 2016</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <relatedItem>
               <bibl>
                  <author></author>
                  <title>Photograph Album of Early Los Angeles, UCLA Library Special Collections</title>
               </bibl>
            </relatedItem>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl/>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body>
         <div type="article"><!-- Enclose each paragraph of your text in a new <p></p> tag. -->
            <p>The Photograph Album of Los Angeles created by Mrs. Armitage S.C. Forbes consists of a series of photos documenting the history and development of Los Angeles and surrounding areas in California from the 1800s to 1900s. Two of the photos in this album collection, both titled “Rabbit Drive Fresno Co. California,” captures a rabbit drive in Fresno. In the first image, a mass of dead bunnies are surrounded by hunters. In the second image, a herd of bunnies are escaping from an enclosure.</p>
            <p>Starting in the mid-1800s, people settled in Fresno, sparking the growth of a new California city. The abundance of land available for cultivation attracted many farmers to the area (Palmer); however, the overpopulation of jackrabbits negatively affected agricultural production. This erupted into the Fresno rabbit drive of 1892 where people slaughtered thousands of jackrabbits (Carle), resulting in significant consequences that impacted the environment and the people of Fresno.</p>
			<p>Jackrabbits have survival instincts and characteristics that have allowed them to expand their population rapidly. Their physical features such as muscular legs that allow them to move quickly and sensitive ears make their survival chances high (Palmer). They make homes under bushes, and shrubs in the west are ideal homes for jackrabbits. Furthermore, jackrabbits are not affected by extreme climates (Palmer). The land in the west provided plenty of food such as bark, shrub leaves, and herbage (Palmer). Jackrabbits’ population boom was also caused by their reproduction speed and their position in the food chain; their main predators included coyotes and golden eagles (Steenhof). Although the golden eagle did prey on jackrabbits, coyotes were the main predators. As jackrabbits’ numbers increased, coyotes’ numbers increased as well (Stoddart). Coyotes mainly feed on jackrabbits, but their predation rate was not sufficient to regulate the booming reproduction rate of jackrabbits. They multiply rapidly, and there are few predators to keep their population in control (Palmer). Eventually, the jackrabbits’ growing population made the farmers worry about damages to their crops, which leads them to hold rabbit drives.</p>
			<p>Rabbit drives were actually well organized events that were efficient in exterminating large numbers of rabbits. The drives began with a selection of a certain area of land up to several square miles in size (Kansas Historical Society). Next, all the participants, sometimes ranging in the thousands, lined up about twenty to thirty feet apart on the four sides of the selected area (Kansas Historical Society). The people would proceed to create loud noises and slowly advance toward a fenced area in the center of the square (Kansas Historical Society). This process was meant to push the rabbits toward the middle. Once the rabbits were trapped inside the fenced area the people would begin to kill the rabbits by clubbing them (Kansas Historical Society). The participants restrained from using firearms because of the danger with so many people in the area (Kansas Historical Society). Unfortunately, the rabbits were rarely eaten because of fear of “rabbit fever” a disease that was common among the rabbits (Kansas Historical Society). This whole process was extremely efficient because one drive could kill tens of thousands of rabbits.</p>
			<p>The Jackrabbits destroyed farmers’ crops and livestock which caused a great loss to their agriculture and profits (Kansas Historical Society).  In spite of this, they were killed as much for sport as protection of agriculture (Kansas Historical Society). The photos suggests the truth of these statements, where mass amounts of dead jackrabbits are accompanied by the farmers smiling in satisfaction, believing that their pest problem was under their control.</p>
			<p>Ecosystems are delicate organizations of nature. When any single variable of an ecosystem is removed or damaged, the entire environment suffers. The Fresno Rabbit Drives removed large number of hares in a very short period of time, leaving the ecosystem to suffer in their absence. Predators, like coyotes, lost their prey, forcing them to replace the rabbits with a different form of food, such as sheep and other small animals (Knowlton and Stoddart). Other predators, such as mosquitoes, were also forced to find another source of food, such as  humans. The main goal of the rabbit drives was to save the crops, which would benefit society, but the human activity actually “indirectly created a food web impact that affected human livelihoods in an unanticipated fashion” (Berger, 116). Although the the rabbit drives had the intention to better the environment for the crops to thrive, they unintentionally upset the balance of the ecosystem.</p>
			<p>Some of the dead jack rabbits were shipped off to San Francisco and large cities to be sold as food while their skins were used for fur (Palmer). Because jackrabbits had low monetary value on the market, the profits made from the rabbit drives would never equate to the amount of money that the farmers had lost to their crop failures (Palmer). The Fresno Rabbit Drive was a method for the farmers to minimize their economic destruction and control the large rabbit population (Palmer). Even though the rabbit drives lead to negative consequences on the environment, they helped the farmers escape an economic crisis, indirectly leading to the emergence of a great agricultural city.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      
      <back>
         
         <note type="mapmarker"><!-- this will be the title & text in your map marker pop-up -->
            <placeName type="neighborhoods">Fresno Rabbit Drive, Rabbit Drive</placeName>
            <geo>-118.441517 34.074956</geo><!-- geocoordinates here. !! enter in the longitude first, then the lattitude !! you can look up coordinates here: http://www.gps-coordinates.net -->
            <p>Fresno was one of the main cities in California in the 1800-1900s. In 1892, population of Jack rabbits increased because of the abundance of food supply (Palmer). Population boom of rabbits caused them to become pests for the farmers and the people of Fresno (Palmer). The county agreed to pay the bounty for the number of rabbits caught. With the bounty on rabbits and rabbits ruining their lifestyle, people cornered the rabbits to mass slaughter them (“Fresno’s Great Rabbit”).</p>
         </note>
         
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl><!-- At least one of your citations should be for the object(s) your are writing about -->
               <bibl>"American Jack Rabbit History." American Jack Rabbit History. N.p., n.d. Web. 16 Nov. 2016.</bibl>
			   <bibl>Berger, Joel “Cautionary wildlife tails: learning to fail or failing to learn” Ignoring Nature no More: The Case for Compassionate Conservation. Edited by Marc Bekoff. 2013. Print. University of Chicago Press.</bibl>
			   <bibl>Carle, David. Water and the California Dream: Historic Choices for Shaping the Future. Berkeley, CA: Counterpoint, 2016. Print.</bibl>
               <bibl>"Fresno's Great Rabbit Drive." The San Francisco Call 22 Mar. 1896: n. pag. California's Digital Newspaper Collection. Veridian. Web.</bibl>
			   <bibl>Kansas Historical Society. "Jackrabbit Drives." Kansapedia. N.p., Mar. 2009. Web. 14 Nov. 2016.</bibl>
			   <bibl>Knowlton, E.F. and L.C. Stoddart. 1992. “Some Observations from Two Coyote- Prey Studies” In Ecology and Management of the Eastern Coyote, edited by A. Boet, 101-121. Frederiction, NB. Wildlife Research Unit, University of New Brunswick.</bibl>
			   <bibl>Palmer, Theodore Sherman. The Jack Rabbits of the United States. Washington: Govt. Print. Off., 1896. Print.</bibl>
		<bibl>Photograph album of early Los Angeles, “Rabbit Drive Fresno Co. Calif”(484, 482), pg 31, 34</bibl>
			   <bibl>Steenhof, Karen, and Michael N. Kochert. “Dietary Responses of Three Raptor Species to Changing Prey Densities in a Natural Environment.” Journal of Animal Ecology, vol. 57, no. 1, 1988, pp. 37–48. <ref type="url" target ="www.jstor.org/stable/4761"> JSTOR.</ref></bibl>
			   <bibl>Stoddart, L. Charles et al. “Coyote Responses to Changing Jackrabbit Abundance Affect Sheep Predation.” Journal of Range Management, vol. 54, no. 1, 2001, pp. 15–20. <ref type="url" target="www.jstor.org/stable/4003521"> JSTOR.</ref></bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         
         <div type="images">
            <figure xml:id="[fig1]">
               <graphic url="../images/rabbit_1.jpg"/>
               <head>Pg 31- Rabbit Drive Fresno Co. Calif 484</head>
               <note type="attribution">Forbes, A.S.C., Mrs.; 1925. Image courtesy of UCLA Library Special Collections.</note>
               <figDesc>Dead bunnies surrounded by hunters.</figDesc>
            </figure>
			<figure xml:id="[fig2]">
               <graphic url="../images/rabbit_2.jpg"/>
               <head>Pg 34- Rabbit Drive Fresno Co. Calif 482 Alexander Photo</head>
               <note type="attribution">Forbes, A.S.C., Mrs.; 1925. Image courtesy of UCLA Library Special Collections.</note>
               <figDesc>Herd of bunnies escaping from an enclosure.</figDesc>
            </figure>
            
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
