<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Lyrical Map of the Concept of Los Angeles</title>
                <author>Libros Schmibros</author>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>UCLA Libraries</publisher>
                <date when="2014">Fall 2015</date>
            </publicationStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <relatedItem>
                    <bibl>
                        <author></author>
                        <title>Lyrical Map of Los Angeles, UCLA Digital Library Collections</title>
                    </bibl>
                </relatedItem>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl/>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text>

        <body>
            <div type="article">
                <p>"In Fall 2011, the Hammer Museum invited Libros Schmibros to be artist-in-residence under the curation of Public Engagement. As part of the environment we created in the museum’s ground floor gallery, we asked artist J. Michael Walker to trace the literature of Los Angeles cartographically. His work with Libros Schmibros was subsequently purchased by UCLA Special Collections for permanent display in Powell Library.</p>
                <p>The map is now part of UCLA’s Digital Archive and can be viewed either in its entirety or in part here. Get the artist’s perspective here."</p>
            </div>
        </body>

        <back>

            <note type="mapmarker">
                <placeName type="arts">Los Angeles</placeName>
                <geo>-118.442289 34.071572</geo>
                <p>The Lyrical Map of the Concept of Los Angeles is held at UCLA's Powell Library.</p>
            </note>

            <div type="bibliography">
                <listBibl>
                    <bibl>“Literary Map of Los Angeles.” Libros Schmibros Lending Library. Web. 23 Sept. 2015.</bibl>
                    <bibl>Walker, J. Michael. "Lyrical map of the concept of Los Angeles," UCLA Library Digital Collections, 2011.</bibl>
                </listBibl>
            </div>

            <div type="images">
                <figure xml:id="fig1">
                    <graphic url="../images/lyrical1.jpg"/>
                    <head>Lyrical Map title</head>
                    <note type="attribution">Image courtesy of ...</note>
                    <figDesc>Image of the hand-drawn title of the work. Reads: Lyrical map of the concept of Los Angeles. J. Michael Walker, 2011. Designer &amp; Cartographer.</figDesc>
                </figure>
                <figure xml:id="fig2">
                    <graphic url="../images/lyrical2.jpg"/>
                    <head>Close up of Lyrical Map poem</head>
                    <note type="attribution">Image courtesy of ...</note>
                    <figDesc>Conceptual drawing of female figure with a poem enclosed in the figure.</figDesc>
                </figure>
                <figure xml:id="fig1">
                    <graphic url="../images/lyrical3.jpg"/>
                    <head>Father Boyle</head>
                    <note type="attribution">Image courtesy of ...</note>
                    <figDesc>Drawing of Father Boyle with youth, reads: "Nothing stops a bullet like a job," Father Greg Boyle, Homeboy Industries.</figDesc>
                </figure>
            </div>
        </back>
    </text>
</TEI>
